Ryan Daniel Evans

Akron, OH 44319 • (330) 671 1076 • rdevans87@gmail.com

Technical Customer Support Specialist

Summary:

Multifaceted customer service specialist with proficient understanding of technical troubleshooting and valuable experience supporting a variety of software products and services on the web. Selfmotivated team player with a strong work ethic and desire to learn new skills.

Core Skills:

- Software Sales (Final Draft)
- Technical Support (CRM, Salesforce)
- Customer Service (CRM, Helpdesk)
- Product Implementation (SAAS)
- QA Testing (Jira, Agile/Scrum)
- Web Design (HTML, CSS)

Employment:

IMDb.com, subsidiary of Amazon.com **Customer Service Specialist**

08/2019 - Present

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps using CRM tools and resources.

- Collaborated with development team to file bug reports, track unresolved tickets, and manage customer relationships.
- Built fast and effective working relationships with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.
- Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make data-driven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.

Cast & Crew Entertainment Services, LLC. Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst

04/2018 - 08/2019

Assisted with product implementation, software QA testing, and technical support for digital

payroll products and services: Studio+, Start+ (SAAS)

- Provided on-site/remote product demonstrations and training sessions to end-users.
- Tracked bug reports, enhancement requests, and software updates using Agile project management Scrum in Jira.
- Acted as liaison between senior leadership to communicate software updates and releases to customer support team.
- Collaborated with product manager and engineering team on development of implementation and end-user training.

Final Draft, Inc., subsidiary of Cast & Crew Entertainment, LLC. 04/2016 - 04/2018 Sales Associate

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016) & Final Draft 11 (2018).

 Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.

Unified Pictures 03/2015 – 04/2016 Production Executive

Facilitated the relationship between financiers and executive producers on upcoming film projects.

- Communicated effectively under pressure during long periods of high call volumes to provide concise and accurate information to accredited investors.
- Gained valuable understanding of production workflow, budget costs, and private placement memorandums.
- Demonstrated flexibility and persistence to create consistent pipeline of accredited leads for finance department.

Macy's 03/2012 – 03/2015 Sales Supervisor

Managed associates to provide the highest level of customer service through monitoring selling behaviors; taught detailed product knowledge, communicated policies and procedures.

- Consistently exceeded store goals using MAGIC selling best practices to increase customer engagement.
- Ability to analyze daily reports and identify opportunities to increase retail sales within assigned departments.
- Collaborated with merchandising team on upcoming promotional events and changes to department floor plans.
- Directed sales associates to connect with customers in order to build quick rapport and provide an outstanding shopping experience.

Education:

The Ohio State University
Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies

Completed: August, 2011

Expected: June, 2021